（信(しん)）何が良かっただ…
What's there to be "glad" about?!
You... and you... and you...!
てめえも… てめえも てめえも！
ふざけたこと言ってんな！
Cut the shit!
Hey, old man!
（信）おい おっさん
Piao is... Piao is...
漂(ひょう)は…
漂は…
Piao is dead!
漂は死んだんだぞー！
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）ンンッ…
Hey! Say something!
おい 何か言え！
（昌文君）漂だけではない
ほかにも大勢 死んだ
It isn't just Piao. A great many others also died...
これは戦争なのだ
This is a war!
Wh... What did you say?
な… なんだと…
You bastard...!
てめえ…
Cut the bullshit!
ふざけやがって！
（貂(てん)）あっ… ヤバッ！
You piece of shit!
（信）この野郎！
I'm sorry for the disturbance, your highness.
（壁(へき)）お騒がせいたしました 大王
What shall I do with this one?
この者 いかがいたしましょう？
（昌文君）隅で寝かせておけ
（壁）ははっ！
Let him sleep in a corner.
Sgir!
Ancient China.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望は解放されていた
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
human desire was unleashed.
And a storm of violent wars erupted for 500 years...
戦乱の嵐が
500年にわたって吹き荒れ
100を超えた国々は
７つに淘汰(とうた)された
until over one hundred states were reduced to merely seven.
そして今 西の果ての国 秦(しん)から―
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the state of Qin in the far West.
大いなる歴史が
生まれようとしている
これは
戦乱の時代を生き抜いた―
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
the warring era to its end!
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
Seboo
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuitous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
KoolKidsK
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Qpax
Now's the only time.
～♪
The Path to Great General
Here you go! While you wait!
（貂）はいよ お待ち
（貂）ハァ…
Could you guys at least say "yum!" if you like it and "yuck!" if you don't?
うまいなら“うまい！”
まずいなら“まずい！”
…くらい言ってくれよな
…て そんな空気じゃないか
I guess it's not that sorta atmosphere.
Geez...
（兵士１）
まったく… ひどい戦いだった
We're really in a bind...
（兵士２）
まさか あんなことになるとは…
I never thought something like that would've happened.
Yeah, even our lord, Changwenjun got put through all that trouble...
（兵士３）ああ　我が殿
昌文君さまも ご苦労なされた
Changwenjun?!
ウッ…
（信）昌文君？
おい 貂！
今 昌文君って言ったよな？
Hey, Diao! Did you just say "Changwenjun"?!
お… 俺じゃねえよ
It wasn't me!
あんにゃろう どこ行きやがった？
That bastard!
Where the hell'd he go!
Ow...
あいててて… ちくしょう 誰が…
Dammit, who was it?
まだ動くのはムリだよ
You shouldn't be moving around yet.
Course, you're not the only one in rough shape.
まあ 動けそうにないのは
お前だけじゃないけどな
Everyone came here for Zheng's sake.
みんな
政(せい)のために ここまで来たんだ
ああ 本当に良かった
I'm really glad.
まったくだ
大王さまが ご無事で何よりだ
Seriously. What's most important is his highness is all right.
Did you see Lord's face before?
先ほどの殿の顔 見たか？
I've never seen him cry like that!
あんな泣き顔 俺は初めてだ
I'm glad we risked our lives to get here!
命を懸け ここまで たどりついて
俺は良かった…
In the escape play, our biggest miscalculation was the appearance of
（壁）こたびの脱出劇
我らの最大の誤算は
王騎(おうき)将軍の出現です
General Wang Qi.
あの方が出てこられるとは
予想外でした
We never anticipated he would come.
Basing on his personality, I would've expected the general to be indifferent to the strife going on inside the palace, but...
将軍の性格から考えて―
宮廷内の争い事には
無関心と考えておりましたが
We may truly have fallen pray to Wang Qi's plan back then.
（昌文君）
あのとき 私は まんまと王騎の策に
はまったのかもしれません
（政）策？
Plan?
Yes.
はい　あの激しい乱戦の中
我らの戦いは―
In the middle of that fierce melee, our battle was suddenly taking place
いつしか 束達(つかだち)の丘の上に
atop the Shuda Hills...
And there...
そこで…
ウリャー！
（昌文君）な… なにぃ！
What?!
ウワーッ！
And so I narrow managed to escape death, but...
（昌文君）こうして
私は 九死に一生を得ましたが
そこで 戦場を
離脱しなければならなかったのです
I had to break away from the battlefield there.
I blundered...
不覚…
No, thinking about it now,
いや 今にして思えば なぜ
長々と王騎と一騎打ちができたのか
I wonder how it was I could fight one-on-one with Wang Qi for so long...
With the ability that man has,
あの男の実力をもってすれば―
私など たちどころに
一刀両断にできたはず
he could have cut me in two there and then.
あれは 明らかに
私を戦場から引き離すための策
It's clear that he had a plan to separate me from the battlefield.
He's a man of many mysteries.
謎の多い方です
心のままに羽ばたく―
He flies on his whims.
The Mystery Bird of the State of Qin, General Wang Qi.
“秦国の怪鳥” 王騎将軍…
The legendary general who served my great-grandfather, King Zhao,
（政）我が曽祖父 昭王(しょうおう)配下の
伝説の将軍か…
huh...?
Um... I thought you might be hungry.
（貂）
あの… 腹減ってるかと思って
Thanks, Diao.
すまんな 貂
My king, who is this?
（昌文君）大王 この者は？
（政）黒卑村(こくひむら)で命を救われた
She saved my life at Heibei village.
Her name is He Liao Diao.
河了貂(かりょうてん)という
（昌文君）そうでしたか
I see.
But youngster, those are some odd clothes you have on.
しかし
小僧 変わった格好をしているな
俺は 山の民だからな
That's because I'm one of the Mountain People.
Oh? So you could say this is your land, as well.
ほう… すると お前にとっても
ゆかりの地ということか ここは
Maybe.
かもな
大王さま よろしいでしょうか？
Your majesty, may I?
What is it?
何だ？
Her and the other one who helped you in Heibei Village...
すると 先ほどの者も黒卑村で？
（政）ああ
Yes,
his name is Xin.
名を信という
あの者のおかげで俺は ここにいる
It's thanks to him that I am here right now.
そして 信は―
And Xin was... Piao's friend.
漂の友だ
He was... Lord Piao's...
彼が漂どのの？
Lord Piao?
（貂）“漂どの”？
Your majesty, if I might have your permission,
大王さま
お許しをいただければ あの若者に
漂どのの最期 話したく存じます
I would like to talk to that young man about Lord Piao's last moments.
Xin!
（貂）信！ お～い 信！
Hey, Xin!
Zheng's calling you!
政が呼んでるよ
なんか 話を聞かせたいんだってさ
He wants to talk to you about something.
What's with you? Zheng's calling you.
（貂）どうしたんだよ？
政が呼んでるんだよ
You depressed, Xin?
落ち込んでるのか？ 信
Would you quit blabbering?!
ゴチャゴチャうるせえんだよ！
なにが“政が呼んでる”だ！
Who cares if Zheng is calling me!
I'm trying to think right now!
俺は今 考え事してるんだ
用があんなら 向こうから来やがれ
If he wants me, tell him to come here!
Who's Zheng?
政って誰だ？
Was there somebody here by that name?
そんなヤツ いたっけ？
（兵士２）うん？
Zheng?!
（３人）“政”？
You're not talking about his majesty, are you?!
それって
まさか 大王さまのことか？
（信）ああ
（兵士２）何のマネだ 貴様！
Yeah.
What do you think you're doing?!
Calling him your majesty is part of showing respect!
大王さまの御名(みな)を口にするのも
恐れ多いのだぞ！
政が いいって言ったんだよ
（兵士４）まだ言うか！
He said "Zheng" is fine!
You're still saying it?!
大王が呼んでるんだよ 信
（兵士たち）あっ…
The king is calling you, Xin!
C'mon!
早く　壁って人が伝えたいんだって
（信）だから 何だよ？
That Bi guy wants to talk to tell you something.
Geez, about what?
About Piao's last moments.
漂の最期だってさ
（信）ハッ…
分かった
Got it.
Wait for me!
待ってくれよ
The blowgun?
吹き矢？
But where're the darts?
でも 矢は？
Ah, there he is.
I got used to seeing corpses in the village, but touching them is so gross!
死体は 村で見慣れてっけど
触るのは気持ち悪い…
Where are they?
どこだ？
Not over there.
（ムタ）そこじゃないべ
ウワーッ！
Do not make a ruckus.
騒いじゃダメだべ
（貂）でで… 出た
If they find out I'm alive, they'll finish Muta off.
生きていることバレると
とどめを刺されてしまうべ…
な… なんだ おっさん
まだ生きてたのか
What the hell old man, you're still alive?
Muta's life force is a menace...
ムタの生命力は脅威だべ
is what Muta would like to say, but Muta will die soon.
…と言いたいところだが
もうすぐ死ぬべ
So leave Muta in peace.
だから そっとしといてくれだべ
Okay, but in exchange you've gotta give me your poison darts.
じゃ そっとしといてやるから
代わりに 毒矢をくれよ
Muta's poison darts...?
ムタの毒矢をか？
ああ　俺 強くなりたいんだよ
Yeah. I wanna get strong.
You're Bi?
（信）あんたが壁か？
昌文君さまの臣下で副長の壁と申す
I am Changwenjun's retainer and the vice captain, Bi.
I heard... you wanted to talk about Piao.
漂の話をするって聞いたぜ
Yes. I wanted to make certain you know what happened.
そうだ　この話は 君に
是非 知っていてもらいたいのだ
My lord!
（壁）殿ーっ！
（王騎）ンフッ…
Lord Bi! Orders!
（兵士）壁どの ご指示を！
Protect the carriage!
御車を守れ！ たとえ
その身が切り刻まれようとも―
Even if your body is chopped to pieces, don't let them get to that carriage!
御車だけは守るのだ！
（斬る音）
（兵士）ウワッ！
Only Lord and I knew that it's a double.
（壁）替え玉のことを
知っているのは 殿と私の２人だけ
In order to make the plan succeed, I raised my voice to inspire the troops.
この策を成功させるため―
私は 声を張り上げて
兵たちを奮い立たせようとした
しかし
王騎の軍は あまりにも強かった
But Wang Qi's army was...
too strong!
Don't falter! Stay focused!
ひるむな！ ひるむな！
Due to that, our ranks were thrown into disorder and the carriage was left alone.
しだいに隊列は乱れ
御車は孤立していった
Lord Bi!
（兵士）壁どの！ 御車が！
The carriage!
（兵士）ウワッ！
（壁）終わった…
俺たちは ここで全滅する
It's over...
We're going to lose everything here...
I had given up on everything. But then...
私は 全て諦めた　だが そのとき…
（漂）諦めるな！ 隊列を組み直せ
密集して突破を図るぞ！
Don't give up! Reform your ranks!
Crowd together and we'll attempt to break through!
Gather around the king!
（兵士）大王のもとに集まれ！
（兵士）一気に突破するぞ！
Let's break away in one burst!
With Lord Piao's words, we went from despair to
having the flames of battle in our hearts relit!
漂どのの ひと言で―
絶望しかけた我らに
再び 闘争の灯が ともった
I honestly couldn't believe it!
私は 正直 信じられなかった
In front of the Wang Qi army that was feared across the states,
諸国が恐れる王騎軍を前にして―
he lead us without any falter.
全く ひるむことなく
我らを率いているのが―
Even though he was just a low-class nameless boy...
身分の低い無名の少年などとは
L-Lord Piao!
ひょ… 漂どの
That figure was truly... that of a king!
しかし その姿は―
もう 王であった
I had thought that with this push, we would be able to break through!
私は“この勢いならば突破できる”
そう確信した　しかし…
I believed that, but...
Vice Captain! Split the squadron in two, and head to rescue Changwenjun!
（漂）副長！
隊を二分して
昌文君の救援に向かわせよ
But my king! With this vigor, we can break away!
（壁）しかし 大王
この勢いなら突破できます！
The king needs Changwenjun!
王には 昌文君が必要だ！
いいな？ これは命令だ！
（壁）はっ！
Understand?! This is an order!
Yes, sir!
（鬨(とき)の声）
（壁）大王 右方より新手が！
My king! A fresh supply of troops are coming from the right!
（漂）まだ あんな数が…
They still have that many...?
It looks like this won't...
そう簡単には いかないみたいだな
be that simple!
Xin... give me strength...
信… 俺に力を
Let's go, Xin!
いくぞ 信！
That's the king! Go!
（兵士）あれが王だ！ いけ！
Just try to take my head!
この首 取ってみよ！
Thanks to Lord Piao, the enemy's pursuit towards us was weakened.
（壁）漂どののおかげで
我らへの敵の追撃は弱まった
Okay! Now we can make it through the enemy line!
（壁）
よし！ これなら敵陣を抜けられる
He broke though!
突破した！
Everyone! The king is all right! Keep moving forward!
皆の者 大王は ご無事だ！
このまま行け！
I was sure that I would reunite with Lord Piao here, safe and sound...
（壁）てっきり 漂どのは無事で
ここで再び会えると思っていたのに
I feel such chagrin...
無念だ…
おい 政
ひとつだけ聞きたいことがある
Hey, Zheng.
I have something I want to ask you.
What is it?
俺は頭がよくないから
具体的なことを教えてくれ
I'm not too smart, so I want to to be straightforward with me about this.
何だ？
If you safely back to the palace, what're you going to do with me?
I guess since you're the king, you can do whatever you want, right?
お前を無事に王宮に帰せたら―
お前は俺を どうしてくれるんだ？
やっぱり 王さまだから 望みは
何でも かなえてくれるのか？
My desire is to become a general,
俺の望みは将軍になることだから
could you do something like make me a general?
俺を将軍にしてくれたりするのか？
（２人）アア…
Why bring this up all of a sudden?
どうしたんだ？ 急に
Piao really... was incredible.
やっぱり 漂は すげえ
漂を英雄のように
語ってくれた壁のあんちゃんを見て
After hearing this guy, Bi, talk about Piao like he was a hero,
改めて そう思った
it gave me a firm reminder.
He always knew...
あいつは いつも知ってたんだ
what he needed to do to get something...
手に入れるためには
何をすればいいのか
だけど 俺は何も知らない
あいつが全部 知ってたから―
But I don't.
He knew it all, so I just thought if I hung around with him, I'd be fine.
あいつに
ついていけばいいと思ってた
だけど… もう漂は いない
But... Piao is gone now.
今の俺には 何も分からないんだ
And right now, I don't know a thing about it.
So, please tell me.
だから 教えてくれ
How can I become a general?!
俺は
どうしたら将軍になれるんだ？
Poison darts are dangerous, so Muta will give you numbing darts.
（ムタ）毒矢は危ねえから
しびれ矢をやるべ
（貂）ちょっと不満だけど
しょうがねえや
I'm kinda disappointed, but I guess there's nothing I can do.
Mountain Person He Liao Diao's fighting power has risen!
山の民 河了貂！ 戦闘力上昇なり！
そっとしておいてくれた礼に
忠告してやるべ
As thanks for staying quiet, Muta will give you advice.
You won't be all right just by sticking with that young king.
あの若い王についていっても
いいことないべ
From what Muta heard, his only ally is that bearded old men.
聞くところによると
味方は あのひげじじい１人だべ
Right now.
（貂）今はな
でも ホントは 呂氏(りょし)っていう
強力な味方がいるらしいぞ
But apparently we have a strong ally called Lü Shi.
なんか 遠征中みたいだけど
He's just on a campaign right now.
It is unfortunate, but you are very mistaken.
残念だが それは大きな間違いだべ
Currently, this state's system that places achievement above all else.
（政）今この国は
実力至上主義の体をなしている
The age where one can become a general merely by being born of a noble or warrior family has ended.
貴族 士族が―
生まれ持った階級だけで
将軍を務める時代は終わった
It is a structure where if you appear on the battlefield and continually produce winning results,
戦場に出て
他に負けぬ成果を上げ続ければ―
your rank will rise and you can reach the position of general.
階級が上がっていき
将軍に行き着く仕組みだ
Piao said that, too. I know that much!
そんなことは
漂も言ってたから知ってるさ
Could you say it more concretely?
もっと具体的に教えてくれっての
Unfortunately, it's impossible for you.
残念だが お前はムリだ
（信）なに！
What?!
What do you mean?!
どういうことだよ？
An army is primarily composed of regular soldiers from noble or warrior families,
軍とは主に 貴士族である正規兵と
一般庶民から
徴集した徴集兵から構成される
and conscript solders collected from commoner families.
しかし 今のお前は―
But as you are now, not only can you not be a regular solder, but you cannot even be a conscript soldier.
正規兵は もちろん
徴集兵にもなれん
You really don't know a thing, do you?
（昌文君）
本当に何も知らんのだな お前は
Conscripted soldiers are from houses listed in the family register.
徴兵されるのは
戸籍登録されている家
And houses with above-standard amounts of riches.
しかも水準以上に財を持つ家からだ
But for you, who doesn't even have a house to live in,
しかし―
住む家もない身のお前は
武功どころか―
Not only cannot gain military achievements, you cannot even set foot on the battlefield.
戦場に行くことすらできないのだ
（信）えっ…
Don't get so down.
そう くじけるな
将軍というものは 貴族 士族でも
簡単に目指せる代物じゃない
The rank of general isn't something even nobles or military families can gain easily.
I see...
（信）そうか…
I understand.
分かった
（昌文君･壁）うん？
（昌文君）分かった …のか？
（信）ああ 分かったぜ
You understand?
Yeah, I get it!
Then somehow, I've just gotta get Zheng back to the palace,
じゃ 政を王宮に帰して―
何とかって弟と
何とかって大臣を倒したら―
somehow beat the younger brother and the chancellor,
俺は 土地をもらって
家を建ててもらって―
get a land, build a house,
財をもらえばいいんだな？
（昌文君･壁）ウッ…
and get some riches!
That's the whole of it.
そういうことになるな
Then it's a deal!
約束だぞ
（政）承知した
Acknowledged.
ヘッ… こりゃ面白くなってきたぜ
ヘヘッ！
This's gonna be interesting!
In exchanged, you need to work ten times as hard.
（政）
その代わり 10倍 働いてもらうぞ
（信）冗談じゃねえ 100倍だ！
You've gotta be kiddin'! It'll be a hundred times!
Zheng! Is it true that General Lü won't come back until Zheng is killed?!
政！ 政が殺されるまで 呂軍は
戻ってこないって本当なのか？
( Flag - Lü )
Chancellor Lü,
（兵士）呂丞相(じょうしょう)さま
王都より早馬が まいりました
a horse has arrived from the capital.
Furthermore, it's telling of Jie Shi's rebellion.
またしても
竭氏(けつし)の反乱を伝えるものです
（呂不韋(りょふい)）首をはねよ
（兵士）はぁ？
Cut off his head.
That is a strategy of the Wei Army designed to allow them to escape our Lü Army's encirclement.
（呂不韋）それは この呂軍の
包囲を逃れたい魏(ぎ)の軍の策謀である
その伝令の首をはねよ
Cut off that messenger's head.
Even knowing of Jie Shi's rebellion, Lü Shi won't come back?
（壁）竭氏の反乱を知っても
呂氏は戻ってこないと？
Th-That's ridiculous!
そ… そんなバカな！
大王さまを失って 最も困るのは
呂氏ではありませんか！
The one most worried about losing his majesty should be Lü Shi, isn't it?!
Bi... You still have yet to grasp the true fearsomeness of Chancellor Lü.
壁 お前は まだ呂丞相の
本当の恐ろしさが分かっておらん
What the hell's he talking about, Zheng?!
一体 どういうことだ？ 政
Lü Shi is waiting for me to be killed and for Chengjiao to take the throne.
呂氏は 俺が殺され
成蟜(せいきょう)が王に即位する時を待っている
At that moment, Lü Shi will be able to loudly extol Jie Shi and Chengjiao's injustice.
それをねらって 呂氏は
成蟜と竭氏の非道を高らかに叫び
20万の兵を率いて
堂々と 咸陽(かんよう)に攻め入る
And leading 200,000 soldiers, will launch a grand attack on Xianyang.
With Xianyang becoming a battlefield,
戦場となった咸陽では―
王族が 戦渦に巻き込まれて
みな命を落とすかもしれない
the royal family will be caught up in the battle, and possibly all die.
王族が全滅したとき 国民は
誰を次の王に押し上げると思う？
With the entire royal family wiped out, who do you think the citizens will push to be the next king?
Lü Shi...!
呂氏…
What the hell?! Quit messing around!
何だよ そりゃ！ ふざけんなよ
呂氏って
お前の味方だったんじゃねえのか？
Didn't you say Lü Shi was your ally?
これじゃ お前 王宮には
敵しかいねえじゃねえかよ！
With that, it sounds like you had nothing but enemies in the royal palace!
I told you, didn't I?
だから 言ったろう
俺は 過酷な戦の
荒野を歩む 力なき王だと
"I am a powerless king walking the wastelands of a relentless war."
だ… だけど 何か手があるだろう？
B-But there must be something we can do, right?!
Hey! Changwenjun!
おい 昌文君！
Unfortunately. With our current forces, we cannot even get close to the capital.
残念だが 今の我らの力では
王都に近づくことすら かなわぬ
All we can do is watch over the movements of Lü Shi and Jie Shi here, and wait for an opportune time to recover.
ここは 呂氏 竭氏の動静を見守り
再起の時を見計らうしかない
No, Changwenjun.
（政）いや 昌文君
I want to return to the palace on the earliest day possible.
俺は １日も早く王都に帰るぞ
But my king!
しかし 大王…
Regardless of my being alive or dead,
（政）俺の生死にかかわらず
竭氏は 呂氏との全面戦争の
準備が整いしだい―
as soon as Jie Shi is prepared for all-out war with Lü Shi,
成蟜を
無理やり王位に就かせるだろう
he'll forcibly place Chengjiao on the throne.
The battle between Jie Shi and Lü Shi is something big enough to divide
呂氏 竭氏の戦いは
国を二分するほど大きなものになる
内戦を起こさせる前に
俺は 玉座に就き―
this country in two.
Before a civil war breaks out,
王都を正常に戻さねばならん
I must take the throne and return the capital to normalcy.
It... It's impossible, my king!
ふ… 不可能です 大王
我らが力は微弱
Our forces are feeble!
And now, without joining forces with Lü Shi or Jie Shi,
しかも今 秦国で―
呂氏 竭氏に くみせず
我らを助ける軍勢などありませぬ
there is no army in Qin that can help us!
そうだろうか？
Is that right?
Do you have an idea, Zheng?
何か手があるのか？ 政
あっ！ その吹き矢
あのおっさんのじゃねえかよ！
That blowgun!
Doesn't that belong to that old man?!
It doesn't matter! I got it now!
（貂）
いいじゃねえか　もらったんだよ！
（信）ちょっと見せろよ
（貂）イヤだよ！ もう俺んだぞ
Lemme see it for a sec!
No! It's mine!
I ain't taking it from ya, I just wanna see it!
取りゃしねえから見せろって！
（昌文君）アア…
イヤだ！
（信）なんだよ ケチくせえな！
No!
Let me see, dammit!
（昌文君）あった…
There is a way.
Did you say something, my lord?
殿 何か おっしゃいましたか？
あ… あったぞ ひとつだけ
呂氏 竭氏に くみせぬ大軍勢が
Th-There is a way!
Just one...
A great army not joined with Lü Shi or Jie Shi!
I've been thinking about that since I arrived here.
ここに来たときから
俺も それを考えていた
B-But it's been 400 years since we've allied with them...
（昌文君）し… しかし
彼らとは 400年も前に…
（政）可能性は低いが
会いに行くしかない
The chances are low, but we have no choice but to go meet with them,
the Mountain People.
山の民と…
And the one who governs them, the Mountain King!
彼らを治める山の王に
kowaresou na kokoro tsumugu youni
壊れそうな心 紡ぐように
To weave together my breaking heart
yume no kakera mitsume (No more cry)
夢のカケラ見つめ (No more cry）
I gaze at the fragments of a dream (No more crying)
me no mae ni wa tsuki ga utsushidasu
目の前には月が映し出す
The moon I see before my eyes
kono mune no yakusoku
この胸の約束
reflects this promise in my heart
～♪
namida ga nokoshita kioku sae mo
涙が残した記憶さえも
I won't turn away from my tearful memories
waraiatta kako sae furimukanai
笑いあった過去さえ振り向かない
nor the past where we laughed together
（壁）そうか　君たちは
知らないのか “馬酒兵(ましゅへい)”の話を…
Voice of soul
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）戦慄する信たち
底知れぬ闇に うごめくのは
血に飢えた民なのか？
Voice of you
kanashimi nara kitto tsuyosa ni kawaru hazu
悲しみならきっと 強さに変わるはず
Sadness is sure to turn into strength
次回 “恐ろしき山の民”
I won't cry
I won't fear
I won't stop
takaku tobeba kitto sora no mukou ni todoku
高く翔べばきっと空の向こうに届く
If I jump high enough, I'm sure I'll reach beyond the sky
Voice of mine
Yeah
Voice of soul
Preview
I see... You all didn't know...
the story of the Majiu Soldiers.
Xin and the others shudder.
Wriggling in a bottomless darkness
The Terrifying Mountain People
will they find a people who were friends?
End
Next time,